https://www.isu.edu/ogc/general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/privacy-statement/

Skip to Main Content
×
COVID-19 Information and Updates
Privacy Statement:
Idaho State University (ISU) is committed to protecting your privacy and developing processes and procedures to safeguard your personal data. This Privacy Statement applies to information submitted to ISU, including through the use of ISU’s websites, and governs the way we collect, store, use, and share data.
By providing information to ISU, you consent to the data practices in this Privacy Statement.
COLLECTING PERSONAL DATA
ISU collects “personal data”, which includes Personal Sensitive Information (race, ethnic origin, religious or philosophical beliefs, health data, sexual orientation, and criminal convictions), and Personal Information, which is any other information concerning the data subject that is created by ISU or provided to ISU, including your name, home address, work address, telephone number, and e-mail address, as well as demographic information that is not unique to you.
Information about your computer hardware and software is automatically collected, including IP address, browser, domain names, access times, and referring website addresses. This information assists ISU in the operation and quality of our services, and provides general statistics about use of ISU’s website.
Information that you directly share through ISU’s website, such as public message boards, may be collected and used by others. You may interact with ISU on several social media networks, and information you share is through a third party site.
ISU is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on websites outside of ISU and its websites, including links to other websites controlled or maintained by third parties. Please be familiar with the privacy statement of each and every website that you visit that collects your information.
USE OF PERSONAL DATA
ISU must collect and use your information to operate the website and deliver services to you, and to inform you of other products or services that are available from ISU and its affiliates. ISU may contact you through surveys to conduct research on current services or potential new services that may be offered in the future.
ISU does not sell, rent, or lease customer lists to third parties. However, ISU may contact you on behalf of a third party business partner about a service or offering that may interest you, but will not transfer your information to that third party business partner.
ISU may share data with trusted third parties to assist with statistical analysis, to send you email or postal mail, to provide customer support, or to arrange for deliveries. ISU may also share data with trusted third parties who have entered into a contract with ISU to support its operations. These trusted third parties are prohibited from using your information for any other purpose, and are required to maintain your confidentiality.
ISU keeps track of the websites and web pages that you visit within ISU. This data is used to deliver customized content and advertising within ISU to those whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area.
ISU will disclose your information, without notice, if required by law or with the good faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with legal process served on ISU, to protect and defend the rights and/or property of ISU, and to protect the personal safety of users of ISU or the public. ISU will not use or disclose Personal Sensitive Information without your explicit consent.
COOKIES AND IDENTIFIERS
A “cookie” is a small data file that is written to your hard drive that contains information about your visit to a website. Information is not stored in cookies. ISU has “first-party cookies” that are set through ISU websites, including Google Analytics. There are also “third-party cookies” set by third parties through ISU websites.
An “anonymous identifier” is a random string of characters used for the same purpose as a cookie, but on platforms where cookie technology is not available, such as mobile devices.
If you prefer not to receive cookies, configure your browser not to accept them at all, or to notify and require your approval before setting new cookies. This may cause some websites or web pages to malfunction, and/or you may have to provide the same information each time you visit those websites or web pages.
THIRD PARTY SERVICES
ISU uses Google Analytics and Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting. Google Analytics uses cookies to help websites analyze how users use the website. The information gathered about your use of the websites (and possibly your IP address) is transmitted to and stored by Google.
ADVERTISING
ISU and third party vendors, including Google, use first-party cookies and third-party cookies together to inform, optimize ads, and serve ads based on a person’s past visits to ISU websites, and to display content-specific advertisements to visitors that have previously visited ISU websites when they go to other websites. They are also used to report visitor ad impressions other uses of the ad services, and how interactions with those ad impressions and ad services are related to visits to ISU websites.
ISU uses data from Google’s interest-based advertising or third-party audience data such as age, gender, and interests, with Google Analytics to report, optimize, and deliver interest-based advertisements.
OPT OUT
You can opt out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display network ads by using Google Ad Settings (see https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads/). Please also see Google’s Privacy Policy: https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/.
SECURITY OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA
ISU uses its best efforts to secure your information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure, ISU secures the information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. When information, such as a credit card number, is transmitted to other websites, it is protected through encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.
STUDENT RECORDS
Student records are protected by the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA), which is a federal regulation that assigns rights to students and responsibilities to educational institutions with regard to student educational records, including release of information from those records. For more information, see the Registrar’s Office website: https://www.isu.edu/registrar/student-resources/ferpa/.
CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT
ISU may periodically change this Privacy Statement as necessary, and encourages you to review this Privacy Statement to keep updated on how ISU is protecting your information.
COMPLIANCE
If you have comments about this Privacy Statement or believe that ISU has not adhered to this Privacy Statement, please contact gdpr@isu.edu.
General Counsel
ComplianceContracts / Affiliation Agreements SubmissionGeneral Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)+General Information about the LawGlossary of TermsWhat ISU Collects and SharesHow ISU Uses InformationData ProtectionPrivacy StatementYour RightsHealth Programs GuideISU Policies & ProceduresLinksPublic Records Request SubmissionRisk ManagementStaffWorkers' Compensation
Policies, Changes, & News:
ISUPP policies under 30 day review
University's Safety Statement
Risk Management:
Travel.State.Gov
Go to Travel Maps
Go to Advisories and Alerts
